Atul Meshram

UX / UI Designer & Developer

www.atulmeshram.in

in www.linkedin.com/in/atulmeshram



+91-8050606549

atul.meshram.akm@gmail.com

SHSR layout, Bangalore, PIN - 560102, INDIA

About Me

I am passionate about the way people use technology. I love to interact with the users to understand their expectations and unpleasant experiences from the product, and use their insights to create simple and beautiful interfaces that have a high degree of usability.

Education

Master of Computer Applications Specialisation in Computer Graphics NIT Karnataka, Surathkal July 2013 - June 2016

8.5 CGPA

GNIIT - Software Engineering NIIT Ltd.

December 2010 - April 2013

A+ Grade

Bachelor of Computer Applications

PRSU, Raipur

July 2008 - June 2011

78%

Class 12th

CBSE - All India

May 2007

81%

Class 10th

CBSE - All India

May 2005

80%

Professional Work Experience

BT Business App - Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd.

UX/UI Designer

[July 2016 - Present]

A mobile application providing all business services to BT Group PLC customers.

My goal was to understand and analyse customer needs; interact with them to create a good user experience. I have designed application flow, created wireframes and mock-ups, reviewed and guided the developers to get the expected output and design.

Apple App Store: https://goo.gl/m7EY5Z Google Play Store: https://goo.gl/1KkVrL

UKB SaaS - Accolite Software India Pvt. Ltd.

Software Engineer - Intern

[January 2016 - July 2016]

Mobile products and related services module of UKB SaaS project owned by BT Group PLC. I have coded fully functional application modules; using C#, AngularJS and ASP MVC architecture based on .NETTechnology. I have written unit test cases on JasminJS by configuring KarmaJS framework. I learned organisation's process of fulfilling customer needs and business objectives.

Voluntary Work Experience

Placement Cell Portal - NIT Karnataka, Surathkal

Web Application Developer

[December 2014 - December 2015]

Official web portal for students and companies enrolled for campus recruitment.

While pursuing master degree at NIT Karnataka, I served my college as Web Developer and Database Administrator of placement.nitk.ac.in

UX/UI Skills

Web & Mobile UX/UI Patterns **UX Strategy & Planning** User Research Wireframe & Prototyping Interface Design Interaction Design **Heuristic Evaluation**

Programming

JavaScript HTML5 CSS3 C# CSwift (Beginner)

Web Frameworks

AngularJS 4.0 NativeScript TypeScript **GSAP** Bootstrap Node.JS .Jasmine.JS KarmaJS

Softwares & Tools

Sketch & Plugins Flinto Adobe Photoshop Adobe Illustrator **AxureRP InVision Google Analytics** Visual Studio Code

Leadership

Design Strategy **Team Coordination Work Review Project Planning Training & Mentorship**

Design Personas

Comparative Analysis

Usability Testing

Wireless Headphone 'Air' - App Concept | https://goo.gl/UFCS3g Farmers' Suicides - Infographic Report | https://goo.gl/ibxSBF